about this opportunity, made it
attractive to you, and what are you
looking forward to continuing to work
with?
>> Well, I mean, I think we all know that
relationships are important. I mean,
Robert Sol and I have known each other
for many years. Had a chance to work
with them last year. Um, it was a great
experience and I think we're we have a
lot of the same philosophies, uh,
although we're different. Um, and I
think that mixture kind of has that
proper tension and um, you know, we had
a chance to kind of tear apart the
defense last year, look at things we
didn't want to do and what we did want
to do based on our experience at
different places and then just kind of
incorporate it there and uh, just to
keep that part of it going I think was
very intriguing to me.
>> Terry McCormick, uh, mainstream media.
What what about this job intrigues you
in terms of knowing that Robert's going
to call the defense and what does that
make your role on game day and
throughout the week?
>> Yeah, I think um you know I don't want
to say it's ego is not involved. You
know, I think everybody wants to be
valued in the organization or valued on
the team and I think that's where I'm at
right now is just I really enjoyed last
year. I mean, I love football, love
looking at scheme, love all parts of it.
And there's great deal amount of trust
with Robert and I. So, I think it'd be
different if it was maybe on game day,
you were more of a spectator. All right.
Done all the work. Now, he just calls it
and you sit back. But that's not what it
was like last year. There was constant
communication between Robert and I
throughout the game. We talked about
things. So that part of it I think
knowing that hey we have constant
communication looking at things as they
develop and what we want to get to um
you know made it very attractive.
>> Ron Davenport ESPN you've been with
Robert Salah for quite some time. You've
known him for some time. How how have
you seen him grow just just over the
years, especially after the experience
with the
>> I I figured that would come up because,
you know, here he is. We hired him as a
quality control coach back in 200 what
11 in Seattle and to have him as a
quality control coach and then go to
Jacksonville, bring him on as a
linebacker coach. And then when I went
to uh the Chargers, he was going to come
as the linebacker coach until Kyle
Shanahan called and we talked and he had
a chance to interview there. So I know
I've seen them you know for that first
seven eight years you know in the early
you know 2011 12 13 in that time frame
and then we are part but had constant
communication but I just think that um
you know where he's grown from a
linebacker coach to a coordinator you
know I think his greatest asset is he
really does see the big picture I mean
he is a big picture guy you know hey
this is how I see it he's always trying
to stay a step or two ahead of the game
you know that's what's um That's what's
cool about him and I think he does a
great job relating to the players. Great
energy, enthusiasm um for the game and I
think it rubs off on the players and the
coaches.
>> Paul Kharkski from paulkuharski.com.
Could you talk us through kind of uh end
and edge what you guys are looking for
uh kind of bodywise and skill-wise from
those two positions and and how
different one side might look from the
other. I you know what I think that just
talking general terms in general terms
you know I think that one end is maybe a
end on first and second down and then
might have the ability to slide inside
on third down where the other end is
maybe a true rusher. You know he's on
the end first or edge first and second
down and third down as well
>> and in the dirt most of the time. So
>> you know that's what we're looking at
all those things right now. what's the
best for our personnel and you know
we're in the beginning stages of just
looking at that big picture. I guess
with Tennessee and when when you bring
up the stylistic similarities,
differences between you and Robert, can
you kind of go toward that about that?
What is the push and pull? What do you
guys fundamentally agree on and what are
the places that kind of
>> Yeah, I think fundamentally like I mean
obviously the system we agree on. I
think going about like I'm very um um
he's look at the big picture. I'll tear
apart look at all the little things that
go along with it you know and say hey
how does this affect this portion if we
do this you know look at you know deeper
into it and he's provides the big
picture now to say that he doesn't look
at that part of it uh that that'd be
inaccurate but I think as we work
together it kind of evolved more towards
that
>> Steve Layman from New Champ 5 how do you
view your role in terms of the game
planning within the week and then
specifically what happens on game day
and do you think it changes much from
San Francisco to now given he now has
the huge umbrella of
>> head. I I think that, you know, it was
always, you know, let's look at all
aspects, you know, whether it's first
and second down, third down, red zone,
and I I'll throw out ideas. Hey, Gus,
what are your thoughts in the red zone?
You know, what are your thoughts on
third down? Um, looking at film, and
then we throw them out there, but
obviously he's the decision maker.
There's things last year that came up
that he'd say, "That's a good thought,
but I really want to go in this
direction, you know, and it's like,
that's great." And then there's
sometimes it would stick. So I think it
was more just to keep them you know say
let's challenge each other. Um well we
always believe I think within the
organization you challenge one another
but never attack never make it personal
but in order to get better you have to
have challenges and I think that's where
there's great trust amongst us that we
know it's not coming from a bad place
it's coming from a great place and as
you know camaraderie amongst the staff
is so important and I think when you
have that trust when you don't have to
worry about that part of it really opens
the door to being challenged. Do you
think it has to change at all now that
he's the head coach? Do you have to take
a little bit more of a
>> No, I mean, he had a lot on his plate
last year, you know, visiting with Kyle
because Kyle and him were really close.
So, you know, I think that that'll
evolve whatever that role looks like or
continues to grow to be, you know, as
far as the input and things like that.
But, I'm really at a good stage as far
as that. I think it's just a part of,
you know, my our job is to serve the
head coach, serve this team, serve, you
know, the organization and go about it
that way. And u I think during my
career, that's what I seem to operate
best when I have that kind of a mindset.
haven't been a head coach and seeing
Robert now with the second chance. You
think the league's kind of sorting
through like the idea of a a play
calling head coach versus a programming
program building head coach and and how
do you kind of view where that's going?
Um I you know it's it's funny you say
that because after I s you know we were
together for that period of time in
Jacksonville and then when we were
separate we talked but the experience he
had in the Jets and then when I was with
him this past year I think you know in
conversations with him how he saw the
big picture not only as a defense but as
a team and the conversations he had with
Kyle I think it was like well you it
wouldn't shock me if he got another
opportunity. You know, there's guys that
you say, "Boy, he needs to be a head
coach." You know, if given the
opportunity, I think he would do really
well. I think that part was first and
foremost being with him last year. I saw
that part of him. Now, the play calling
part of it, too. I think that's part of
it with him. You could that'd be a great
question for him. But I think when
you're a play caller, you just feel even
more a part of it. You know, you're
you're with them on that. And that's how
I think when Robert does that, he
operates really well. And um I think
that's what he wanted to get back to.
>> Jim White with Tennessee Titans.com.
What do you want the defense to be known
for week in and week out just
consistently what you do?
>> Well, we've the pitcher is a fast and
violent defense, you know. So, you know,
it's I don't think you're going to see
45 different coverages, 50 different
blitzes. If we can do that and still
play fast and violent, we'll do it, but
not at the expense of one of those two,
you know. So, I think it's very
important that our players go out there.
We've always had a defense that we felt
like guys could come in early in their
stage, early in their career and play.
And we want to keep that part of it
open. But, um, the game is evolving. I
mean, what it looked like five years ago
to what it is now, um, you know, is
completely different. So, to have those
adjustables, the the things that you
need, the coverage principles and
pressures is important. We're growing in
that area, but always with that in the
back of our mind, never at the uh
expense of being fast and violent.
>> A Toz Sports, you emphasize the speed,
Robert emphasized the speed and the
violence. Tore Swat is a guy this team
has put a lot of resources into. You
guys historically run a 4-3 and he's
more of a 3- four nose. His size is the
selling point, but is is there a role
for somebody like that in your defense?
Well, I think, you know, to be honest
with you right now, I mean, we're
talking about staff. We're going through
scheme. We're, you know, giving the
scouts a good idea what each position
looks like. You had conversations. We're
really excited about all the guys. And
let's just I, you know, I've always
believed that when you come into a new
situation, the previous staff has done a
good job. There's obviously some good
things that have taken place with them.
Our job is to continue to add to what
they've already built and take it to
another level. And also, I think that's
very important as coaching staff, we
give the players a fresh start. I think
in the years I've done it, when a new
staff comes in, that's what they're
hoping for. Man, I just hope I have a
fresh start that you don't talk to
everybody in the building, get all these
notions of who I am and what I'm all
about, and then you base your opinion
off of that rather than just meet me,
watch me play, and then make judgment.
And so, I'm really trying to stay in
that world. I think Robert is too, you
know, to try to protect that part of it
to say, let's get to know them. We're
excited about everybody in the building
and let's give them that fresh start and
let's see what takes place.
>> The evolution of the game back in the
day with Seattle, you know, your cover
three, it gave offenses fits as they
adjusted. How have you started to adjust
to that adjustment that day?
>> Well, without without getting into too
much detail, you're you're accurate. I
think there's, you know, I think even if
you look at people assume, oh, it's just
cover three. Well, you know, that was
back then, but as time has gone on,
there's more things that have, you know,
been added to the package. But I think
that's what last year we looked at and
said, "All right, how do we, you know,
what are things we're going to take out
of the package and what are we going to
add, you know, that will, you know,
that'll help us, you know, be more
efficient on defense and give us a
chance to be successful."
>> Lauren Walsh with WSMV Sports. Um, how
much do you tailor a defensive scheme to
certain players strengths, some of the
key returners on this roster versus
concepts that you and Robert want to
continue to integrate? I
>> I a great question. I think you got to
be flexible. Uh, because it is all about
utilizing the skill set of the player.
So, if you see a player as a really good
blitzer, you know, a nickel corner is a
really good blitzer, well, I mean, you
should have some blitzes for him, you
know, if that's what he does well. So,
we'll take a look at everybody's skill
set, see what they do well, and then try
to utilize their skill set, and uh along
within the scheme, but that's always an
uh something that we're going to take a
good look at to see what they're good at
and what their strengths are, and then
put them in those positions.
>> Just from a numbers standpoint, the
quarterback position is one of great
need on this team. What are you looking
for in the draft and in free agency at
that position? What What's your type of
quarterback?
>> Right. I think that's again without
getting into too much detail about that.
It's I I think when we're talking with
the scouts, um it's not just a certain
body type or all this, it's more of a
generic, you know, when I'm going to
tell you and not get it out there. Um I
think that we just show them clips over
and over again of the skill set that
we're looking for. Hey, we're going to
ask them to do these five things. Okay?
And so we show those things to the
scouts. This is what we're looking for.
someone that can provide us with the
ability to do this kind of skill set and
then we go from there. So, I I can
appreciate that question, but not to get
in too much detail, I'll handle it that
way.
>> What's appealing to you, Coach Chris
Harris at Channel 4? What what's
appealing to you about a new opportunity
at this stage in your career?
>> I I think that um you always want to be
someplace where you're valued, right? I
think all of us do that. And I think the
relationship that Robert and I um I know
in the off season looking at other
things going on um when Tennessee came
up it was always held in high regard and
that part was very intriguing like the
organization the facilities and you know
the people they have in place there was
a lot of positives. Now, there are a lot
of good people in my belief in the NFL
and I think you go to a lot of places,
but it was extremely positive um with
the Tennessee and um you know, that's
what I'm excited about. You know,
continue to add value uh to a place that
you know is held in high regard across
the league.
>> Ideal for for everyone, but how much
does it trigger
an ideal scenario for you if you're able
to rush for get get home with four?
We've seen a couple Super Bowls in a row
here where the winning team might have
blitzed some, but their base was that he
could get over.
>> I think that I mean any defensive
coordinator would say if you have the
ability to affect the quarterback with
four, it gives you so many more options
in the back end. So yeah, I don't think
anybody would shy away from that if they
if they had that ability. But again,
looking at the skill set, what do we
have? You got to be able to affect the
quarterback. So however we have to do
it, I think that's going to be something
that's always in our mindset. when you
played S when you played the Titans late
in the season. Cory Curtis with News 2,
by the way. Sure. I heard uh Coach
Canahan was obsessed with Jeffrey
Simmons and and what he was going to do.
How much of what you're doing starts
with 98 on a weekly basis?
>> Well, I mean, you talk about holding a
player in high regard, right? Everything
you hear about him, how he practices,
how he works, the effect he has in this
building, uh what kind of a teammate he
is. I mean, we've had conversation, but
that's it's another one. I mean, I'm I
tried to tell Jeffrey, too. I said, man,
I'm we're gonna give you a fresh start,
too. But I you know, I don't know how
fresh that's going to be. We know a lot
about him, but uh you know, I think
we're just excited, you know, that he's
here and part of us and uh you know,
he'll obviously someone that we're very
excited to be coaching.
>> Go ahead.
>> Thank you. What expectations have been
communicated to you from Robert or from
the front office about the speed of this
turnaround? What is the urgency? I guess
>> I I've not had any of those
conversations, but I'd probably be
better with Robert.
>> When you've been franchises like this
before that are coming out of a low
period, what is in your experience the
best?
>> Well, I mean, I think probably the head
coach. Um, I can just speak for when I
was the head coach. Uh, I think that you
want your assistant coaches to have the
mindset, don't worry about that. Just
make sure your players get better. you
know, do everything you can that they
play at the highest level, that they we
utilize their skill set, that if we're
doing something wrong, we get it
corrected. Like, put all that attention
into that and let us worry about, you
know, how fast this is going to take
place. So, I, you know, that's really
where our, you know, talking to our
coaching staff and where they're at and
how my mindset is at that, that's for
them to decide. Right now, we just got
to, you know, get our coaches caught up
in the scheme that we want in place and
then make sure that we visit with our
players and get to know them as fast as
we can.
>> A ton coached a ton of players in this
league. I mean, how would you want your
players to describe what you're like on
a day-to-day basis, teaching them,
coaching them, dealing with
>> I think consistency creates credibility.
So, I think that u you know, someone
that will tell the truth, you know, hey,
we we didn't play well. Let's tell the
truth. We played well, let's tell the
truth. but they're going to consistently
know what they're going to get. I I I
would say by nature I am a 85 and sunny
type guy, you know, every day. Um, you
know, I'm excited about the opportunity.
So, I mean, there's times when you can
flip and obviously if there's things not
working well, but you know, I think
there's I'm a you know, what are the
four things they did well? Now, what are
the two things we need to improve on
type of person, you know, hey, don't
let's not let's not miss the good
things. Let's make sure that we point
those things out because you know
they'll be repeated. But we also it's a
big part of it is accountability and we
know what this standard looks like and I
think that's what Robert and I have it.
We have enough experience together and
know what it should look like that if it
doesn't look like that that's the
accountability piece.
>> Last one.
>> Julian Mittenzone News here in
Nashville. Um you've been in the head
coaching position before. Brian has as
well. How much do you think that's going
to help Robert in his second stint to
lean on you guys knowing that you guys
have all sat in that chair before?
>> Um, I think that I mean we just have
normal conversations about everything,
but he's one thing you'll find out about
Robert, he has a I mean he is pretty in
tune to his vision. I mean he has a
pretty good idea especially now the
experience he had what it needs to look
like, what we need to do and u so I mean
I'm sure there'll be questions come up
but it's it's not like you would think.
it's, you know, he's handling that. He
knows the direction he wants to go. I'm
pretty after being with him last year
even more convicted on on knowing that
aspect. So, I'm sure we'll have
conversations about, but for the most
part, he really has a really good idea
of the standard and and I' I've always
said this with uh Robert, he's always
been a guy that I look at and I said one
of the, you know, the better leaders
create this um the standard and the pace
of of the organization. And that's what
he did in San Francisco. That's wherever
he's been.